[Music]
well hey everybody
good to see you oh my goodness here we
are
we're going to jam on some multiple
choice questions by far
the most frequently asked question i get
is
how do i get better at doing multiple
choice questions
and so we're going to try to tackle it i
made a whole video on it
and the thing that i think a lot of
y'all wanted was
show us some examples you know i think i
did one example in the video but like
okay so that's what we're going to do
for the next i think it'll take like 30
45 minutes
ish to work through some uh
multiple choice for ap us history
and um i would highly recommend
that you that you stay if you're
especially if you're struggling with
multiple choice questions stay
and put in the time do this with me and
it will drastically improve uh what
you're doing with these because what i'm
going to do
is i'm going to show you how i would
look at these
uh how i would interpret them and then
i'm going to try to give you some
tricks to do them faster because that's
another question i get a lot is
i i i think if i had like 10 minutes per
question i could probably get it right
but
i'm under this tight time constraint and
um i just can't do them quick enough so
i'm going to show you what i think is
the best
tip the best strategy for doing these
quickly
and and so yeah it should be good
if you want to follow along with
me no you don't well i'm going to put
them on the screen here
but if you want to look at these
afterwards i got these
questions out of the official course and
exam description published by the
college board
if you want to find that you just search
for a push
ced and it's the first hit it's like a
300 page
pdf and then the exam is all the way
down toward the end um so i didn't want
anybody to think like
i wanted to use official college board
uh
written questions because you know you
never know is
are the questions i'm using actually
going to reflect what i'm going to see
on the test
the answer here is absolutely these are
the the same people wrote these
that wrote the ones that are going to be
on your exam so um
give me 30 seconds uh to tell you a
couple of things uh before we jump right
in
uh the first is um if you have a lot of
questions
about your exam i'm answering those
questions every single day in my
instagram stories you can follow me
uh it's at heimlich history or at
heimler's underscore history
over on instagram and i'm getting
hundreds of questions a day i'm doing my
best to answer them all
but i think they're helping a lot of
people maybe they'll help you too so
instagram
heimler's underscore history also if i
can't answer all your questions
uh there's an incredible community over
on my discord server
uh you can find me over there and all of
them discord dot gg slash heimler's
history
uh i'm telling you that is a magnificent
place to be
uh and then finally last announcement
before we get started
is i am having live review sessions
right here
on youtube with you guys uh we're just
gonna be blitzing
through all the content uh the
may third fourth and fifth at eight p.m
basically eight to nine pm
and uh the exam is may 6th so hopefully
we'll get you ready
um okay so that's all uh if you're ready
to get this party started
i am ready to get this party started um
but i did
i did get a request in the comments for
a dad joke uh so
you know i feel like we ought to start
uh with one of those
um you know
okay
my my mother told me when i was growing
up
that i could be anybody i wanted
it turns out identity theft is a crime
okay all right that's a good one
that's a good one all right if you're
ready let's jump
right in so uh what we're gonna be doing
is looking at uh i think i've got 10
questions here
um and i'm going to go a little slower
um you know i'm not going to be doing
these quickly i want to try to
explain to you what i'm thinking as i'm
looking at these and
how i would go about doing it so we'll
go a little quicker towards the end
but first i want to establish some
principles on how you interpret these so
um so let's look at this first one here
is the
stimulus first thing i want you to do
in every stimulus some of you guys are
going to freak out if the margins aren't
there there we go
the very first thing you do almost
everybody is going to start
right here you're going to start reading
the stimulus don't do that
no no 1 000 times no the very first
thing you always need to do
is come down here and read about what
this document is
who wrote it and when because that is
going to help
you greatly now here's the thing this
tells me
that we're reading the declaratory act
and that's passed by the british
parliament in 1766.
now it just so happens in my 3.3 video i
talked about the declaratory act um and
if you don't know what it is
uh essentially when the colonists
um in america uh uh
fought to get the sugar act and the
stamp act repealed
uh the parliament eventually did repeal
the stamp and the sugar act
um but the declaratory act was
essentially
uh the british parliament saying yeah
but we still have the right to pass any
law that we want like don't
don't go thinking that you guys have any
power over us we're still going to pass
any law that we want so that's the
declaratory act
now the thing is if i know what that is
if i know what the declaratory act is
then
i i i can either read this um stimulus
very quickly or um i i actually in this
case i don't have to read it at all
because as you're gonna see just knowing
what the declaratory act
is i already know the answers to these
questions it's it's pretty astonishing
but
let's suppose you don't know what it is
anyway hold on let me just say this for
a second that's my first
and probably biggest tip for um knowing
for doing these quickly you have to know
your content if you know the content
these are going to go much faster for
you in fact i asked a bunch of teachers
like what what is i got a bunch of
people asking me how do you do these
faster
and by far the most frequent response
was
you just have to know the material if
you know the material really well
they're like
firmly seated in your brain folds you're
gonna do these much
much faster and with a lot more
confidence so
let's go back to this question and
actually read the stimulus
you know just for poops and giggles says
may it please your most excellent
majesty that it may be declared
in this present parliament assembled and
by the authority of the same
that that the said colonies and
plantations in america have been
are and of right ought to be subordinate
unto and dependent upon the imperial
crown
and parliament of great britain and they
of right ought to have full power and
authority to make laws and statutes of
sufficient force and validity
to bind the colonies and people of
america subjects to the crown of great
britain
in all cases whatsoever okay so all this
is saying is
uh regardless of whatever else is going
on with the sugar act and the stamp act
uh the american colonies are subservient
uh under law to the british parliament
and the crown okay so let's look at this
first question
which of the following contributed most
directly
to the enactment of the law in the
excerpt okay now
stop for a second again i want to draw
your attention to something this is
going to be a theme
throughout this whole stream this phrase
right here
most directly which of the following
contributed
most directly to the enactment of the
law in the excerpt now
i'll come back to that in a second i
just wanted to draw your attention to it
so let's look at the answers a the
increasing divergence between
colonial and british culture in the
1700s b debates over how
britain's colonies should bear the cost
of the seven years war or the french and
indian war
c the drafting of a declaration of
independence for britain's colonies in
north america and d conflicts between
colonists and british army leaders over
recognizing
native american sovereignty now
the first thing we need to do if you
have no idea we need to start
by eliminating the wrong answers
and i'm going to show you how you know
what those
are there's going to be two obviously
wrong answers
there's going to be one that is kind of
right
maybe right and then there's going to be
the absolute right answer
so let's get right get rid of the
obviously wrong ones
so first of all c is obviously wrong why
because the declaration of independence
um
was written not as a contribut
it's asking what contributed to the
enactment of this law
the declaration of independence didn't
contribute to it the declaration of
independence was in effect
of the enactment of this law right first
of all this is in 1766
declaration of independence is in 1776.
uh yeah you can read that um so
clearly this is not a cause of this law
it's an effect
of this law so that's number one um gone
uh d is also obviously wrong
conflicts between the colonists and
british army leaders over recognizing
native american sovereignty
now that happened but that was um
after the french and indian war and
they're talking about the proclamation
line
um which is has nothing to do with the
declaratory act so
now we're left with a and b the
increasing divergence between
colonial british culture in the 1700s
and debates over how britain's colonies
should bear the cost of the seven years
war
now take a second think about it which
one
is the right answer the correct answer
is b
now i want to talk about a for a second
before we talk about the right answer
this is what's known in you know test
writing world as
a distractor and
it's it's an evil plot by the reptilian
overlords
in at the college board to ruin your
life
and make sure that you end up living in
a van down by the river
but you're not going to fall for this
but let me show you
why this is considered a distractor
uh the increasing divergence between
colonial and british culture in the
1700s
like if you know your material you know
that's correct
like that actually did happen there was
an increasing divergence between
colonial british culture in the 1700s
um and the fact that the british
parliament passed a law
saying you guys are subservient to us
like that seems like that would be a
result
and it is like the diverging
uh culture uh of the colonial uh
of the colonies and british crown did
in fact lead to the passing of the
declaratory act but
let's go back to that little phrase most
directly which of the following
contributed
most directly and that is
how the colony should bear the cost of
the french and indian war the seven
years war
so so this was a phenomenon a was a
phenomenon that was going on
for uh you know 50 60
years before uh this stimulus was
written
but the most immediate contribution was
the raising of taxes over the french and
indian war
okay good let's move on
two the actions described in the excerpt
most immediately
led to there it is again most
immediately
the actions described in the excerpt
most immediately led to and by the way
before we even get there
if you see that you should you should
register something in your mind okay
the the one the two answers that i'm
gonna
possibly be choosing between are one
that's
um one that's an immediate cause and one
less of an immediate cause okay so let's
go back
a parliament strengthening its approach
to generating tax revenue
new tax revenue in the north american
colonies b major sometimes violent
conflicts emerging between the various
colonial regions
c colonial convention to call for
independence from britain
or d britain delegating greater
authority in the colonial assemblies
now let's eliminate the two wrong
answers first
uh the first obviously wrong answer is
d okay now that's just not even true
like okay we're talking about the
declaratory act here
britain's clamping down on the american
colonies
and you know the answer is the question
is asking
what did the declaratory act most
immediately lead to britain delegating
greater authority to the colonial
assemblies
yeah no that's precisely the opposite of
what it's saying
in the stimulus the other
obviously wrong answer is b
major and sometimes violent conflicts
emerging between the various colonial
regions
to which i say what what is it
what what are you even talking about
that the major
violent conflict between the various
colonial regions that's not even a thing
so now we're left with a and c and by
the way if i know my material i know
that b and d
are obviously wrong now i'm going to be
tempted
to choose c here and
a colonial convention to call for the
independence from britain
however remember we're talking about
most immediately the the declaratory act
most immediately led to what is it the
colonial convention
um to call for independence from britain
or parliament strengthening its approach
to generating new tax revenue in the
north american colonies let me ask you a
question
which one of these came first because
we're trying to figure out what happened
most immediately
obviously this one came first this is
true
but it is not the most immediate cause
okay we got a couple more questions on
this stimulus and then i'm going to look
at some of your comments and see
uh where we stand and see if i can
respond to some of them okay which of
the following was the american colonists
immediate response there it is again
like they love
this which of the following was the
american colonists immediate response to
the attempts of the british parliament
to enforce the claims
made in the excerpt a they acceded to
parliament's authority to regulate
colonial commerce and by the way
if you see a word like that and you're
like i have no idea what that means
don't freak out just try to get it from
the context
they exceeded the parliament's authority
to regulate colonial commerce b
they it means they just you know rolled
over and let them do it uh
b they denied the power of the british
king over the colonies see they sought
an alliance with the fran with france
against great britain
d they initiated boycotts of imported
british goods okay so
we're eliminating the wrong answers
clearly they the
american colonies did not roll over and
let parliament just
do whatever they wanted in the colonies
past whatever laws um
and uh clearly it's also not c
because uh them seeking an alliance with
france against great britain
that's happening outside the time period
that's a that's a different time period
we're actually talking about the
revolutionary war here that's when
the alliance against great britain with
france occurred
so that's outside
the time period um
of of the prompt and so now we're left
with b
and d now correct answer
d they initiated boycotts of imported
british goods now did they also deny the
power of the british king over the
colonies
yes they did they absolutely did and
specifically
in a in documents like the declaration
of independence
etc but the immediate the most immediate
response
was the boycotts of imported british
goods
okay number four debates over the claims
of the british parliament in the excerpt
most directly contributed to which of
the following later characteristics of
the united states government so this
time they are asking you
to uh go outside you know go forward a
little bit in time
so um so which of the following
uh or the declaratory act um
caused most directly most directly
contributed to which of the following
later characteristics of the united
states government um
okay so the here's an example of
four answers well let me give you the
answers a the reservation of some
governmental powers for the states b
the enforcement of term limits for the
president c the establishment of
taxation power in congress
or d the practice of judicial review by
the supreme court okay
now here's an example of one that you're
not going to
find a wrong answer that's like outside
the time period or
you know anything like that um this one
you're really going to be looking for
which of these has like a direct
connection
to what the stimulus is talking about
okay the stimulus is talking about
taxation against the colonies right
okay so that so keep that in mind now
back here
um the the first obviously wrong answer
is
b enforcement of term limits for the
president does that have
anything to do with taxation no it does
not
uh the other obviously wrong answer is
the practice of judicial review by the
supreme court
uh that has nothing to do with taxation
but you're going to see judicial review
and you're gonna be like oh i remember
that oh that's a word that i know
uh and you know it's i've i
i even know how to define it you'd be so
excited you're gonna be like a
like a little toddler on the floor who
sees a crumb of a doughnut and you're
like
you go you go after it because that's
what toddlers do
um but not you my friend not you let's
go back
so um so the the one that you're going
to be tempted to choose
is this one right here the reservation
of some governmental powers
for the states now is that a feature of
the one of the later characteristics of
the united states government
absolutely it is but what are we talking
about
most directly contributed
we're talking about taxation in the
colonies so
it's going to be c the establishment of
taxation power
in congress they didn't want they wanted
taxation power to be
in the hands of the people
not in the hands of a monarch okay
so we got through our first four
questions let's see
how we're doing uh over here in the
comments um
how y'all feeling about that feeling
good
everyone said a yes yes they did
uh okay
we got some people getting messed up so
here's what i would suggest
um don't uh
let's say for for the rest of these
don't put the answer in the comments
that way uh or in the chat that way
everybody can get it on their own and
not get messed up
okay so
uh i ate spaghetti for dinner thank you
for asking
um what else
um let's see how is it see congress
didn't have
tax power initially they only got them
after the confederation fell apart
without it
yes but listen to the question come back
let's go right back to it the question
is
which of the following uh contributed to
the later characteristics of the united
states government
okay so later is the
is the is congress after the fall of the
fall of the confederation of the
um the dissolution of the articles of
confederation
like isn't that after what we're talking
about here so yeah that's why
that's why um
my confidence is shrinking no it's not
no i
i see it i'm gonna i'm gonna i'm gonna
pump it up with some
confidence you got this i mean look look
look
this is the this is i'm not gonna say
it's not hard it is hard
but it's doable it's doable if you
understand
how these things work now would this
have been better
if if i had done this or you know you
had learned this
you know seven months ago yeah but guess
what
it's not seven months ago it's it's a
week before the exam
and you know what we're gonna figure it
out we are going to figure it out and if
you want to get a good score
you can put in the work i i promise you
you put in the work and you'll be fine
okay um my confidence see
that's what i'm talking about that's
what i'm talking about okay
uh let's go back into
um let's go back into the next questions
all right
you ready next question
we're gonna go forward in time a little
bit to 1860.
all right so again if you're trying to
do this quickly
you see republican party platform 1860
that's where you start
always start there that you know a lot
already like there's a lot that you can
know about whatever is going to be said
in this
stimulus just by looking at what it is
where it comes from and when
it was written so the normal condition
of all the territory of the united
states
is that of freedom that as our
republican fathers
when they had abolished slavery in all
our national western territory ordained
that no person should be deprived of
life liberty or property without due
process of law
it becomes our duty by legislation
whenever such legislation is necessary
to maintain this provision of the
constitution against all attempts to
violate it and we deny the authority of
congress
of a territorial legislature or of any
individuals
if you give legal legal existence to
slavery in any territory of the united
states
okay look look like if you know
what the republican party was all about
in 1860 which is to say one year before
the civil war
you already knew all this stuff like all
of that you're not surprised by that so
you can read it quickly and understand
what it's talking about now
let's look which of the following best
serves there it is again
best serves as evidence for the claim
that our republican fathers had
abolished
slavery um in all our national territory
okay so what's what's some evidence we
can use
to s that the republicans could use to
support that
our republican fathers abolish slavery
in all our national territory okay
let's get rid of the wrong answers first
the ban on the transatlantic slave trade
implemented in 1808
surely not uh why because
that didn't ban any that didn't abolish
slavery it just abolished the slave
trade
slavery was alive and well after 1808 uh
so that that can't be the answer
um the other um obviously
wrong answer is uh b
relationship with george washington and
thomas jefferson to slavery
again their relationship to slavery was
complicated
they admitted it was a moral evil but
they certainly
didn't do much to abolish the
institution so we're left with
c and d do you know which one it is
don't put it in the chat don't do it
restrain thyself
the answer is
c the provisions of the northwest
ordinance regarding
slavery when the northwest ordinance was
established it banned slavery in all
territories so that's what they're
talking about
our republican fathers had abolished
slavery in all our national
territory okay um now
of course it can't be uh it can't be d
either because
the agreement to count three-fifths of
enslaved people for representation in
congress
um that i mean it actually has nothing
to do
with banning slavery it has everything
to do with accounting for slavery so
that has nothing to do with it now let's
go on to the next one
the ideas expressed in the excerpt were
most
directly influenced by the what
nativist movement free soil movement
texas independence movement
temperance movement let's move through
this one a little quickly first of all
it's not the nativist movement because
the native movement has
first of all nativists would probably
not be in favor of
abolishing slavery but nativism really
doesn't have anything to do with slavery
it's more about it's more
uh reaction against immigration and
immigrants coming into the country so
that one is
um not on the table uh the other um
obviously wrong one is the temperance
movement that happens
outside the time period um so we're in
uh the temperance movement isn't really
going to come into full force
for another you know 40 you know 35 40
years or so
um then you've got the texas
independence movement
texas think about texas how did texas
come into the union
texas came in as a slave state right
so um this whole idea of
you know banning slavery congress has no
authority
to uh give a legal existence to slavery
yeah texas isn't gonna have anything to
do with that obviously
it's the free soil movement free soil
movement is exactly what it sounds like
it was the campaign to um
to create free states um
and uh and end slavery so
number 10 republicans asserted that
political leaders could not give
quote legal existence to slavery in any
territory of the united states end quote
in order to express opposition against
the a idea of popular sovereignty
exemplified by the kansas-nebraska act b
removal of american indians from their
homelands see recruitment of laborers
from
for northern factories and
de-application of california for
statehood
you know the answer don't put it in the
chat don't do it
take that clicky finger right away
the answer is a
now um it's not b because the removal of
american indians from their homelands
while
it is something that happened has
nothing to do with giving legal
existence to slavery
in any territory of the united states
okay
nor does the recruitment of northern
laborers for northern factories have
anything to do with
slavery in the territories of the united
states um it certainly can't have
anything to do with california because
just like i asked you to think about
texas here
think about california here california
entered as what kind of state
i'm i'm saying that like you're going to
say something back to me it ended as a
free state
so um so
they're they're asking th this uh quote
right here
uh republican leaders republicans
asserted that political leaders could
not give legal existence to slavery in
any territory in the united states
in order to express opposition against
the application of california no of
course not it's it's coming as a free
state so they're not going to oppose
that
they're going to oppose the idea of
popular sovereignty
exemplified in the kansas nebraska act
remember
popular sovereignty was the idea that
for the territories that are applying
for statehood into the union
they are going to decide for themselves
whether they are going to be
free states or slave states so clearly
um they're opposing that right there
okay
i hope you're tasting the sauce already
i hope your you're tasting the sauce
let's see how we're doing over in the
comments i can't keep an eye on them
because i'm trying to do all this
but i do want to see what you guys are
saying
do a dbq question i did that last year
it was the worst day of my life
um i mean maybe i should i don't know i
don't know but
just so you know it's not fun um
okay sometimes i think i just think
straightforward
i don't overthink the answers so i think
it's useful yeah yeah i mean here's the
thing when you're under pressure
as i've fond of saying when you're under
pressure the time is
ticking you are dumber than you think um
you
the the pressure shrinks your ability to
to think clearly um but the thing is
some of these aren't as complicated as
you think and so
your dumbed down brain you know can can
interpret them properly um i don't wanna
nobody's dumb i'm just saying like it's
hard when you're under pressure
absolutely um
uh let's see um where would you
recommend that i practice
uh multiple choice questions um the very
best place to get multiple choice
questions is from ap
classroom and unfortunately as a student
you don't have access to that but your
teacher does
so if you need more multiple choice
questions you need to get on the horn
and
ask your teacher to get a bunch of them
for you um
but if for some reason that's that
doesn't work
um you can get a lot of them in my
ultimate review packet uh
any practice book you have is going to
be pretty good i think
amsco is probably the best one but
but yeah so there's plenty of places to
get them um
the question is you know how good are
they um you you want to stick with the
big
names um in review
all right let's try one more let's try
one more um
i changed my answers because i doubt
myself listen
um i understand that i understand that
but
i think this is one of those kind of
things where you just need to trust
yourself
think about it before you answer and
then
and then just put the answer down move
right on
go live your life um trust that gut
trust the fact if you if you know that
you've studied you know you've put in
the work
then just trust your gut and don't
overthink it
okay let's go back let's
go back all right next question we have
uh let's see we've got
four more we got four more you ready
here we go okay a lot of people ask me
about
stimuli with uh pictures so let's look
at one of those
um first of all i'm feeling like a new
color here yeah we need a red
now when you are looking at a picture
um and you're trying to interpret it
this one's actually pretty easy but if
you're looking at like a political
cartoon
you have no idea what to do with it
here's uh two
or here's one method with two parts you
need to look at it
then you need to look through it okay
the way you
look at it is like you just make
observations like
these are things you can put your finger
on so in this particular case
uh i i'm just looking at it and i see
two women
and they are working on a what appears
to be a fuselage
of an airplane i see one white woman i
see one black woman
and i've just made my observations okay
that so now
now that i've looked at it i need to
look through it in that in other words
i need to interpret it like okay what
does that tell me
about the wider world in which it was
produced well
let's go back here and look more closely
at it first of all
we need to know this is in the 1940s
okay what's going on in the 1940s
why would these two women be building
the fuselage of an airplane in the 1940s
well clearly what we're dealing with
here is world war
ii and um and so
women had to go to work because all of
the
all the men are off across the sea
fighting and
so that's that's it that's all i need to
do to interpret this picture i know
everything i need to know about it now
to answer some questions so
the image most directly there it is
again don't miss that don't miss it
the image most directly reflects which
of the following developments during
the early 1940s so which development
a wartime repression of civil liberties
b the emergence of the united states is
a world power
c the limited access to consumer goods
during wartime
or d the wartime mobilization of the
united states society
now here's what i here's where i tell
you that all of these things
are in fact true none of these are false
statements the question is which of them
most directly
reflects the developments that you see
in that picture
now my guess is you're going to be
tempted to go right here
and say wartime repression of civil
liberties because
this this picture is almost a little
tricky because it doesn't just show
women at work it shows women of two
different races
at work and so you're going to come down
here and see civil liberties and go
oh that's it it's about civil liberties
but it's not because this is about
repression of civil liberties
and clearly there you know there's no
repression going on here
there were repression there there was uh
repression of uh
civil liberties during the war both
world wars um but this is certainly not
um showing us anything of that nature
um so so definitely not that one
uh the emergence of the united states is
a world power yeah i mean it does show
the emergence of the united states as a
world power because
world war ii very much led to um
america emerging on the stage as the
most powerful
um you know in competition with the
soviet union
uh state in the world um so
maybe it's this one maybe it's this one
see limited access to consumer goods
during wartime
i mean that's also true that also
happened but that picture
has nothing to do with the limited
amount of consumer goods we're actually
dealing with military goods here
so it's definitely not that one or d the
wartime mobilization of the united
states society
okay the answer is d
wartime mobilization of united states
society now
why isn't it b it's not b because this
is
like a this is a a much
further off larger um
uh consequence of what's going on in
this picture
we're looking for what most directly
reflects
the developments and what most what's
what's the most immediate context of
this
it's that men were gone women had to go
to work so wartime mobilization of the
united states society
bam all right number 12 the image was
most likely intended to promote
popular support for federal civil rights
legislation to end discrimination
b the belief that women should have
rights equal to those of men
c the movement of women into jobs
traditionally held by men
and d access to union membership for all
workers regardless of race or gender now
the question is what is
this image like what what what are the
people who
made this image and and put it out into
the world
what were they trying to promote what
were they trying to argue for
was it popular support for federal civil
rights legislation to end discrimination
no and i know you're going to think that
then they're tricky they're tricky
because they've got a white woman and a
black woman working together
and it seems like that would promote
federal civil rights legislation to end
discrimination
but it's not that why because that's not
going to happen
for another you know at the earliest
maybe 12
to 15 years um with
uh you know the overturning of um
plessy versus ferguson and brown versus
the board of education so this is
outside the time period right here
outside the period that we're
considering um
is it b belief that women should have
equal rights to those of men
do you think that's what this image was
intended to promote
well no no not in the 1940s
um and then d access to union membership
for all workers regardless of race and
gender
well no that really doesn't have
anything to do with
um with what we're talking about there
the answer is
c the movement of women into jobs
traditionally held by men
like yes this this image
was intended to promote
women going into work um
in jobs that were traditionally held by
men men
traditionally worked manufacturing jobs
and
therefore they needed because they were
all gone they needed
women to work those jobs so that's what
it was for okay we got two more we got
two more you feel it
feeling good all right 13.
production activities like those
depicted in the image most directly
contributed to there's your most
directly again i hope if you get nothing
else out of this stream
is to look for those words because that
is going to tell you the difference
between the
right answer and the kind of right
answer production activities like those
depicted in the image most directly
contributed to a
calls to limit arms and naval destroyers
for major world powers
b critical wartime provisioning for the
allies that led to victory
and c efforts to rebuild western
europe's post-war economy
d concerns about the political influence
of the military-industrial complex now
i'm not going to write i'm not going to
do anything on this one i just want you
to figure out the right answer
so which of these most directly
contributed uh
what the building that plane women
building the plane
what did that most directly contribute
to the answer
is wait for it ready b
uh critical wartime provisioning for
allies that led to victory it was the
entry of the united states into world
war
ii and its incredible industrial
capacity that
led uh the allies to victory and so
that's what you're seeing
there's you're seeing them build
airplanes now um
now let's go back here uh calls to limit
arms
like no that nobody's calling anybody to
limit arms
for naval destroyers for the major world
powers in fact
what you're seeing is the increase
of that production um efforts to rebuild
western europe's post-war economy you're
talking about the marshall plan there
um no that that happened after the war
um i mean you know you could draw a long
line of
causation to from them building that
plane to
the marshall plan but remember we're
talking about most directly contributing
and then d concerns about the political
influence of the military-industrial
complex again that happens
after the war is over okay last
question of the evening in the 1950s the
activities of workers such as those
depicted in the image
would be most challenged by okay so
we've got women working
on an airplane women working in
traditional male jobs
what would most challenge that a culture
of conformity that emphasized domestic
ideals for women b
an increased need for dual incomes in
suburban middle class families
or c and c the rise of
second wave feminist movement in the
united states or d the long-term decline
of industrial production
in the united states what
is the answer i'ma sit here and wait
the answer my darlings
is a so talking about the 1950s
okay so clearly it's not the second wave
feminist
uh movement that's going to happen in
the 1970s
um increased need for dual incomes
in suburban middle class families no
that's not going to
be the case because in the 1950s that's
actually going to
um in middle-class families uh women are
more likely to stay home than go to work
um long-term decline of industrial
production oh no
no that all it just increased from there
so
yeah it's absolutely the culture of
conformity emphasized domestic
emphasizing domestic ideals for women
oh my goodness okay
now um
yeah let's this is a good question let
me uh take a few minutes to field some
of your questions
uh what should you do if you read the
question your brain just doesn't
register causing you to reread it over
and over again
um if you are taking the paper exam then
just skip it skip it and come back to it
um it could be i i know that feeling
uh so just skip it and come right back
to it if you're on the digital exam
you can't skip it um so i would say
um just take a minute like
look around like do whatever you have to
do
and and just do your best like that it
is i i
um it's criminal that you can't go back
and forth
on questions because i mean there are
some questions that that just do that to
you
so um so yeah i i hope uh i hope you're
taking the paper exam and if not
that's okay some of the questions aren't
gonna register but do know this
that you don't have to get anywhere near
a perfect score on your multiple choice
in order to earn a five
on this exam like historically
you need to get somewhere between 72 to
76 percent
right on the multiple choice in order to
be you know on track for a five
before you go into the writing so like
that's not bad you missed like 12 or 13
and still be
really good so if one just doesn't
register it's like
okay it's one of the thirteen yeah
whatever leave it
um okay let's keep going
let's see be my apush teacher i would i
would actually
you probably wouldn't like me as an
apush teacher uh i
i i can do this stuff pretty well but
you know your grades would be behind by
like three weeks
and i would be not responding to your
emails because
those are things that i struggle with
very greatly and you would just be
frustrated with me so i'm glad we have
this relationship and not
the other one um
yeah let's let's uh let's see what we
got here is this going to be uploaded
later yes it is
it'll be right on my channel for um uh
for you to rewatch um best way to cover
material this is a great question
best way to cover material is start with
the big ideas and then move down to the
small ideas
most students i know when they start
studying
the thing they do is they start going
right for the bolded words in the text
or they go over to quizlet and they they
you know they're doing flash cards and
that sort of thing that
is the worst way to study because it's
like
um you know it's like throwing all of
your laundry into your closet floor
you've got a whole heap of stuff but
it's not organized what you need
is to build a closet first get some
hangers and then all of those facts that
you just threw in on the floor
then they have a way of being organized
and the way that you do that is you
start with the big ideas you go to the
course and exam description
you look at the learning objectives the
learn for each topic you look at the
learning objectives that's the big idea
that's the question you should be able
to answer
after learning the material for that
topic the historical developments which
comes next
is the slightly the medium-sized idea
these are the things you need to in
order to answer the learning objective
and then
you go down to the specific examples the
illustrative examples like what are
what are a few like i i mentioned
earlier uh you know the sugar act or the
stamp act or the
declaratory act or whatever the these
are these are things once you have the
bigger ideas in place
then you are able to take those smaller
those things you would find on quizlet
or whatever
and put them in a intelligible order
um but i also have a whole if that
doesn't make any sense i have a whole
video on how to study
um so you can go check that out um
all right let's see um
yes khan academy is great for practice
they have
they actually do have some really good
questions um
i'm glad you mentioned that because i
forgot to say that um
yeah kahoot i tried i tried but
unfortunately um they don't the
formatting won't allow like a stimulus
and like multiple questions to go with
it that would have been awesome i would
have loved to see your answers
but you know unfortunately it didn't
work
um
yes prior ap exams absolutely are great
practice because
especially if you can find them with the
answer keys and the
scoring the scoring commentary
you can find those on college board's
website you can just
go go to google and search for them and
you'll be fine
all right last question what if my
teacher screwed me over and we are on
period five
first that's rough and i'm sorry
uh and i wonder if there is uh anybody
else who's in that same position
uh right now but here's the answer the
answer is
it's up to you like that's not fair like
you
you went to school in order to get the
material but at the end of the day
if your teacher's not going to catch you
up it's up to you you're the one taking
the exam not your teacher and so
um that is a rough position to be in i
just want to acknowledge that that was a
rough position to be in but
like i mean i've i i'm i don't mean to
be
all self-promoting and everything but um
my i've heard from a lot of students
that
they they just watch my videos and and
ingest the material take notes and
whatever
and a lot of them say they get fives
like that's
that blows my mind or fours or whatever
so i would say as it's binge time baby
it's binge time all right well let me
give you uh just a couple
of uh final things here to remember help
you remember what we talked about
first of all to get better at your
multiple choice you need to know your
material that is
absolutely number one study that stuff
know your time periods understand how
everything fits in it
and know the material as well as you
possibly can that will make you faster
and it will make you more confident and
then
second when you have wrong answers
um they're either going to be factually
wrong sometimes they are
not too often they're factually wrong
but sometimes they are
but mostly they're going to be wrong
because they're either in the wrong
period remember we saw that quite a few
times
or they're asking for the wrong
historical thinking skill
so the if the question asks for what
caused
something like we saw in that very first
question
and you have an answer that's actually
an effect of
the event in the question well then
that's obviously going to be wrong
okay well guys thank you so much for
joining me you know i love you
and i know that this is a hard season
but there's at least one
bearded bald man in this world
who loves you and who's proud of you and
i just need you to know it's going to be
okay
all right i hope to see you at the live
reviews
uh next week i will see you then
good night